Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books from the library of Édouard Roditi.
  - Einfuehrung in dassstudium der Romanischen Sprachwissenschaft. by Meyer-Luebke, W., 1920. (Box 123)
    C. Winter's; Heidelberg
  - Exil. Gedicht an eine fremde. by Perse, Saint-John., 1949. (Box 123)
    Karl H. Henssel Verlag; Berlin
    Lacking front cover.
  - Expressionism as an international literary phenomenon. by Weisstein, Ulrich., 1973. (Box 123)
    Didier; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author on title page, dated March 21, 1974. Offprint published by Librairie Marcel Didier, Paris, 1973., pages 15-28.
  - Fidelman's complaint. by Rosenfeld, Alvin H., 1969. (Box 123)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author at top of page. Offprint from JUDAISM: A QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF JEWISH LIFE AND THOUGHT, Vol. 18, No. 4, Fall Issue 1969.
  - International character of symbolism. by Balakian, Anna., 1969. (Box 123)
    University of Manitoba; Manitoba
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author on front cover, dated April 19, 1970. Offprint from MOSAIC, Vol. 2, No. 4, Summer issue 1969.
  - Introduction a la litterature romanche (de 1900 a nos jours)". by Gaudenz, Gilda., 1962. (Box 123)
    Universite de Bruxelles; Bruxelles
    Signed by the author on the front cover, 1963. Offprint from REVUE DE L'UNIVERSITE DE BRUXELLES, no. 5 (Juillet-Septembre 1962), p. 1-18.
  - Inventions a trois voix. by Kochnitzky, Leon., [1964]. (Box 123)
    L. Kochnitzky; [Bruxelles]
  - Invisible oiseau. by Scheinert-Servais, Suzanne., [1974]. (Box 123)
  - Joseph Conrad's sentimental journey. A fiftieth-anniversary review. by Bojarski, Edmund A., 1964. (Box 123)
    s.n.; Texas
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author on verso of front cover, dated May 22, 1968. Offprint from THE TEXAS QUARTERLY, Winter 1964.
  - Marguerite Yourcenar. by Blot, Jean., [1971]. (Box 123)
    Editions Seghers; Paris
    With inscription to Edouard Roditi from Jean Blot on half-title page. No. 38 of ECRIVAINS D'HIER ET D'AUJOURD'HUI.
  - Mensch in den Konfliktfeldern der Gegenwart. by Landeszentrale fuer politische Bildung des Landes Nordrhein., 1975. (Box 123)
    Verlag Wissenschaft und Politik; Koeln
  - Proust. A la recherce dup temps perdu. by Crohmalniceanu, Ovid S., s.d. (Box 123)
    August Basel Verlag; Dusseldorf
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from Ovid S. Crohmalniceanu, 12 November 1975. Offprint from DER FRANZOSISCHE ROMAN, n.d., p. 81-114, 331-332.
  - Qui-vive. by Trolliet, Gilbert., [1975]. (Box 123)
    Messeller; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author on presentation card liad in the book. Paperback.
  - Siecle de l'eclectisme. Lille 1830-1930. by Archives d'Architecture Moderne., 1979. (Box 123)
    Archives d'Architecture Moderne; Paris-Bruxelles
  - Sunlight on the wall. by Meyers, Bert., [1976]. (Box 123)
    Kayak; [Santa Cruz, Calif.]
  - Theatre. by Wilde, Oscar., 1954]. (Box 123)
    [Editions Denoe; Paris
  - Vademecum, fuer Studierende der Romanischen Philologie. by Ettmayer, Karl R. v., 1919. (Box 123)
    C. Winters; Heidelberg
  - Allegory from the 'Arabian nights': the City of Brass. by Hamori, Andras., 1971. (Box 124)
    University of London; London
    Offprint from the BULLETIN OF THE SCHOOL OF ORIENTAL AND AFRICAN STUDIES, UNIVERSITY OF LONDON, vol. 34, part 1 (1971), p. 9-19.
  - Arche. by Miguel, Torga., 1980. (Box 124)
    [Presses Universitaires de France; Paris]
  - Busses. by Benson, Steve., 1981. (Box 124)
    Tuumba Press; s.l.
    Copy 194 of 450. Paperback.
  - Byzance radieuse et sanglante. by Theodore, Paul., [1963]. (Box 124)
    Editions du Scorpion; Paris
    Inscription to Jean Louis Barrault from the author, Paris, April 1963, on half-title page.
  - Chateaux de l'industrie. by Archives d'Architecture Moderne., 1979. (Box 124)
  - Child as elder brother of the man in the poetry of Randall Jarrell. by Nejgebauer, Aleksandar., 1973. (Box 124)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Novi Sad, July 4, 1977. Offprint from the ANNUAL REVIEW OF THE FACULTY OF ARTS, vol. 16, no. 2(1973), p. 649-682.
  - China journey. by Sun, Ruth Q., [1973]. (Box 124)
    Temple University Press; Philadelphia
    Paperback. Printed as a keepsake for Friends of Temple University Press.
  - Christopher Marlowe. Dramaturge. by Marion, Denis., [1955]. (Box 124)
    Arche; [Paris]
  - Ecce-homo. Poemas. by Durao, Americo., 1953. (Box 124)
    Guimaraes Editores; Lisbon
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, 1954, on front free endpaper.
  - Ecritures. Avec cent vingt illustrations extraites de l'oeuvre de l'auteur. by Ernst, Max., 1970. (Box 124)
    Point du jour; [Paris]
  - Elegiaques. Florilege poetique. by Madlyn, Leon., [1973]. (Box 124)
    Joseph Foret; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, June 10, 1974,on front free endpaper. Copy 274 of ? Paperback.
  - Genese du roman turc. Au XIXe siecle. by Dino, Guzine., 1973. (Box 124)
    Publications Orientalistes de France; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, January 21, 1974, on half-title page.
  - Grand piano. Or almanac of alienation. by Goodman, Paul., 1942. (Box 124)
    Colt Press; s.l.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, May 1942, on front free endpaper.
  - Guillaume Apollinaire de Flugi d`Aspermont. Rhenane d'automne en Grisons. by Vogel, Alfred., 1970?. (Box 124)
    Cahiers de Presence; Geneve
  - I clandestini del mare. L'emigrazione ebraica in terra d'Israele dal 1945 al 1948. by Sereni, Ada., [1973]. (Box 124)
    U. Mursia & C.; [Milano]
    Dustjacket.
  - Laconiques. by Trolliet, Gilbert., 1966. (Box 124)
    Courrier du Livre; Paris
  - Manon Lescaut, roman moral. by Coimbra Martins, Antonio., s.d. (Box 124)
    Faculte des Letters d'Aix; n.p.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, November 1968, on p. 259. Offprint from EXTRAIT DES ANNALES DE LA FACULTE DES LETTRES D'AIX, vol. 44, p. 259-269.
  - Midas' Picasso. by Werner, Alfred., s.d. (Box 124)
    Antioch Press; Yellow Springs, Ohio
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on p. 546. Offprint from THE ANTIOCH REVIEW, P. 546- 556.
  - Ombre de la pluie. Poemes. by Scheinert-Servais, Suzanne., [1976]. (Box 124)
    Maison Internationale de la Poesie; [Ottignies,Belgique]
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, April 5 1979, on half-title page. Paperback.
  - Politics of culture. by Buchanan, George., 1977. (Box 124)
    Menard Press; London
  - Portfolio. With an appendix, the tender continent. by Vangelisti, Paul., 1978. (Box 124)
    Red Hill Press; Los Angeles
  - Samuel Nomad, NIGHTMARE CEMETARY. by Rosenfeld, Alvin., 1966. (Box 124)
    Brown University; Providence
    Offprint from BOOKS AT BROWN, vol. 21 (1966), p. 207-210.
  - Theoretische stuetzpunkte der musiksoziologie. by Silbermann, Alphons., 1975. (Box 124)
    Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft; Darmstadt
    Offprint from the MUSIKHOEREN, (1975), p. 387-403. Originally appeared in the MUSIK UND BILDUNG, ZEITSCHRUFT FUER THEORIE UND PRAXIS DER MUSIKERZIEHUNG, NO. 4 (1972), P. 61-67.
  - Whitman's open road philosophy. by Rosenfeld, Alvin., [1968]. (Box 124)
    Wayne State University Press; Detroit
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, April 1968, on front cover. Published in WALT WHITMAN REVIEW, vol 14, no. 1 (March 1968) p. 3-16. Photocopy.
  - Au bal avec Marcel Proust. by Princesse Bibesco., [1928]. (Box 125)
    Librairie Gallimard; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, 1929, on flyleaf.
  - Au jour la nuit. by Raval, Marcel., 1932. (Box 125)
    Au Sans Pareil; n.p.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on half-title page. Copy 575 of 910.
  - Celebrations. Poeme. by Manno, Yves di., 1979. (Box 125)
    Dominique Bedou Editeur; Gourdon, France
  - Daluyong. by Gaiano., [1982]. (Box 125)
    MLI Diffusion (AAA); [Paris]
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on half-title page. Copy 353 of ?
  - Dostoievski. Par lui-meme. by Arban, Dominique., 1962. (Box 125)
    Editions du Seuil; s.l.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi form the author, Paris, 1963, on title page.
  - Fortune des jours. by Perol, Raoul., [981]. (Box 125)
    Editions Barre-Dayez; Paris
  - Handrail and the wampus. Three segments of a polyphonic biogriad. by Duff, Charles., 1931?. (Box 125)
    Cayme Press Limited; London
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, August 8, 1931, on front free endpaper. With blue moon poem for Christmas 1931. copy private of 100.
  - Il paese senza tempo. Ed Altri poemi. by Capasso, Aldo., 1934. (Box 125)
    Tipografica Editoriale; Milano
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper.
  - Into the Maya world. by Wright, Thomas E., [1969]. (Box 125)
    Bobert Hale & Co.; London
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front paste-down. Dustjacket.
  - Klaus Mann (1906-1949). Leben und Werk in Texten und Dokumenten Ausstellung zum 75. Geburtsjahr. by Volkshochschule, Kulturgesellschaft der Stadt Ahlen., 1981. (Box 125)
    Volkshochschule der Stadt Ahlen, Kulturgesellschaft (Ahlen)
    Ahlen, Germany
  - Memories of the future. by Wagner, Gordon., 1979. (Box 125)
    Angels Gate Press; San Pedro, Calif.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on the verso of the penultimate leaf.
  - Nouvelle creation. by Suares, Carlo., 1929. (Box 125)
    Rene Hilsum & Co.; Paris
  - Paul Goodman 1911-1972. A memorial for Paul Goodman. by Goodman, Paul. (Box 125)
    Poems of Paul Goodman read at the Community Church, New York, 1982.
  - Poemes. by Pozzi, Catherine., s.d. (Box 125)
    Mesures; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. Limited edition of 410. 200 copies are numbered I-CC, this copy is CXXIV (124).
  - Poems. For small apartments. by Horn, Edward N., 1941. (Box 125)
    Press of James A. Decker; Prairie City, Illinois
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, January 11, 1942, on front free endpaper.
  - Poeti d'oggi. by Capasso, Aldo., 1937. (Box 125)
    Meridiano; Rome
    Contains Diciassette Poesie of Aldo Capasso in POETI D'OGGI, no.4 (1937), p. 7-37. Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on title page.
  - Poets' messages. Chansons de France. by Goll, Ivan., [1940]. (Box 125)
    Gotham Book Mart; [New York]
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, December 25, 1940, on back paste-down. Copy 100 of ?
  - Present difficulties. by Cushman, Don., 1980. (Box 125)
    Cloud Marauder Press; Berkeley, Calif.
    One of 750 copies.
  - Procession Enchainee. by Suares, Carlo., 1934. (Box 125)
    Editions R.-A. Correa; Paris
  - Questions de conscience. Essais et allocutions. by Maritain, Jacques., [1938]. (Box 125)
    Desclee de Brouwer; Paris
  - Se surprendre mortel. by Caminade, Pierre., 1932. (Box 125)
    Editions Chantiers; Montpellier, France
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, May 29, 1932, on front free endpaper. Limited edition of 250. 25 copies are numbered A-Z, this copy is AX.
  - Situation de la poesie. by Maritain, Jacques et Raissa., [1938]. (Box 125)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the authors, on half-title page.
  - Sur un orgue de Barbarie. by Suares, Carlo., 1928. (Box 125)
    Librairie de France; Paris
  - Verite de la lecture. by Dominique Bedou, editor., s.d. (Box 125)
    Impasses; Gourdon, France
    IMPASSES, no.15.p. 8-75.
  - Vesuvius. by Temple, F. J., 1977. (Box 125)
    Capra Press; Santa Barbara, California
    Etchings by Arthur Secunda.
  - Vie extreme. Poeme. Avec quatre dessins de Baldo Guberti. by Trolliet, Gilbert., 1931. (Box 125)
    Editions de "Presence"; Geneve
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author on front free endpaper. Copy 392 of 400. Dustjacket.
  - Acte I. by Delmas, Jean-Jacques., 1981. (Box 126)
    Gourdon Arts Graphiques. Direction of Dominique Bedou.; Gourdon
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front flyleaf.
  - Canisse. by Spingarn, Lawrence P., s.d. (Box 126)
  - David Scheinert. Or passion du juste milieu. by Ferenczi, Laszlo., 1982. (Box 126)
    Editions Louis Musin; Belgium
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from David Scheinert, on front flyleaf.
  - Five plays. by Hitchcock, George., 1981. (Box 126)
    Jazz Press / Papa Bach Editions (co-published)
    Los Angeles
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on title page.
  - Image d'ecume. Poeme et bois d'Abram Krol. by Krol, Abram., 1974. (Box 126)
    Editions Caracteres; Paris
    Limited edition of 270. 250 copies are numbered 1-250. This is copy 202.
  - Lebenslied. Gedichte aus 25 jahren. by Torberg, Friedrich., 1958. (Box 126)
    Albert Langen & Georg Mueller; Muenchen
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Vienna, September 1958, on front free endpaper.
  - Leu. by Delmas, Jean-Jacques., 1982. (Box 126)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, January 30, 1983, on front flyleaf.
  - Mademoiselle de Vissard. Ou France sous le consulat. by Balzac, Honore de., 1950. (Box 126)
    Librairie Jose Corti; Paris
    Limited edition of 1107. 1000 copies are numbered 101-1000 and 100 H.C. This copy is 908.
  - Ni guerre ni paix. by Bosquet, Alain., [1983]. (Box 126)
  - Ode maritime. by Pessoa, Fernando., 1955. (Box 126)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the translator (Armand Guibert), on half-title page. Dustjacket.
  - Patmos. by Voronca, Ilarie., 1934. (Box 126)
    Editions Cahiers Libres; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on half-title page. Copy 275 of 503.
  - Permis de sejour. Poemes. by Voronca, Ilarie., [1935]. (Box 126)
  - Poesie. by Marini, Egle., 1957. (Box 126)
    Edizioni Del Milione; Milano
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on title page. Paperback.
  - Satrileg. by Tauschinski, Oskar Jan., 1983. (Box 126)
    Union Verlag Berlin; [Berlin]
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, May 1983, on half-title page. Dustjacket.
  - Sonnets pour une fin de siecle. by Bosquet, Alain., 1980. (Box 126)
    Gallimard
    Saint-Amand
  - Sprueche der hoelle. by Blake, William, trans., s.d. (Box 126)
    New Years greeting, 1963-1964, from the translator.
  - Three-cornered heart. by Fremantle, Anne., 1970. (Box 126)
    Curtis Books; New York
  - Wand and quadrant. by Logue, Christopher., 1953. (Box 126)
    Collection Merlin; Paris
  - Wein der Goetter. by Kavafis, Konstandinos P., 1947. (Box 126)
    Kentaur-Druck; Maastricht
    Signed by Wolfgang Cordan, on back free endpaper. Copy 78 of 80.
  - Childish jokes: crying backstage. by Goodman, Paul., 1938. (Box 127)
    [5x8 Press]; [New York]
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, December 25,1938, on front flyleaf.
  - Dead of spring. by Goodman, Paul., 1950. (Box 127)
    Libertarian Press; Glen Gardner, New Jersey
  - Free unions - unions libres. by Taylor, Simon Watson, ed., 1946. (Box 127)
    "Printed for editor"; London
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the editor, on verso of front cover.
  - Gespiegelte erde. Gedichte 1953-1963. by Ivask, Ivar., 1967. (Box 127)
    Frederick Ungar Publishing Co.; New York
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Norman, March 30, 1971, on half-title page.
  - Heart's garden, the garden's heart. by Rexroth, Kenneth., [1967]. (Box 127)
    Pym-Randall Press; Cambridge:
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. "This edition consists of 1000 copies, of which 700 are softcover."
  - Historia de garabombo, el invisible. Balada 2. Novela. by Scorza, Manuel., [1972]. (Box 127)
    Editorial Planeta; Barcelona, Spain
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, May 11, 1972, on dedication page. Dustjacket.
  - In another country. Poems 1935-1975. by Laughlin, James., [1978]. (Box 127)
    City Lights Books; San Francisco
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. Dustjacket.
  - Ivre de nuit. by Milbauer, Joseph., [1932]. (Box 127)
    Editions Jean Budry & Cie; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. Limited edition of 515. 500 copies are numbered 1-500, this copy is 380.
  - Laudes regiae. A study in liturgical acclamations and mediaeval ruler worship. by Kantorowicz, Ernst H., 1946. (Box 127)
    University of California Press; Berkeley and Los Angeles
  - Nueve prosas. Ejemplares. by Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1983. (Box 127)
    Ediciones Alfaguara S.A.; Madrid
  - One hundred more poems from the Japanese. by Rexroth, Kenneth., [1976]. (Box 127)
    New Directions; [New York]
  - Ou est mon pere. by Salemson, Harold J., s.d. (Box 127)
    Editions "Anthologie"; Liege, Belgium
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Mescalero, New Mexico, Febuary 25, 1931, on front flyleaf.
  - Private history. An autobiography. by Patmore, Derek., 1960]. (Box 127)
    Alden Press; London
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Febuary 26,1961, on front free endpaper. Dustjacket.
  - Promesse. Accomplie. France-Egypte-Judee. by Cattaui, Heli-Georges., 1922. (Box 127)
    Camille Bloch; Paris
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on December 1933, on front flyleaf.
  - Red jacket. by Goodman, Paul., s.d. (Box 127)
    s.n.; [New York]
  - Selected poems of George Woodcock. by Woodcock, George., 1967. (Box 127)
    Clarke, Irwin and Company Limited; Toronto and Vancouver
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, May 1968, on half-title page. Dustjacket.
  - Signale. Gedichte. by Morell, Pit., 1967. (Box 127)
    Bechtle Verlag; Muenchen and Esslingen
  - Survivals. by Honig, Edwin., 1964. (Box 127)
    October House Inc.; New York
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Providence, June 1,1968, on front free endpaper. Dustjacket.
  - Tausendundeine Nacht. Die schoensten Geschichten. by Arabian Nights., [1965?]. (Box 127)
    Guetersloh; Bertelsmann GmbH
    Translated by Gustav Weil. Illustrated by Arwed D. Gorella. Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the illustrator, April 7, 1966, on half-title page. Dustjacket.
  - Von dem Fischer un Syner Fru. Ein marchen nach Philipp Otto Runge mit sieben Bildern. by Behmer, Marcus., 1954. (Box 127)
    Infel Verlag; Frankfurt
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Berlin, November 7, 1956, on page 27.
  - Well of Bethlehem. by Goodman, Paul., s.d. (Box 127)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, August 1957, on front free endpaper.
  - 52 pick-up. Scenes from the conspiracy. A documentary. by Klappert, Peter., 1984. (Box 128)
    Orchises Press; Washington
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, UCLA, Los Angeles, July 9, 1984, on half-title page.
  - Amities lointaines. by Scheinert, David., [1983]. (Box 128)
    Editions du Pantheon; Brussels
  - Aux portes du poeme. Supervielle, Aragon, Eluard, Reverdy. by Benamou, Michel and Calin, William, ed., [1964]. (Box 128)
    Macmillan Company; New York
  - Badenheim 1939. by Appelfeld, di Aharon., 1981. (Box 128)
    Arnoldo Mondadori Editore; Milano
    Inscription to Eduard Roditi from the author, on title page.
  - Berkeley Street Cannibals. New & selected work, 1969-1976. by Vinograd, Julia. (Box 128)
    West Coast Print Center; Berkeley
    Signed by the author, Berkeley, on verso of the cover. One of 2000 copies.
  - Elegiaques II. by Madlyn, Leon., [1980]. (Box 128)
    Editions Subervie; Rodez, France
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, August 28, 1980, on half-title page.
  - Erkundungen. by Sabahattin, Ali, et al. Nine Turkish storytellers., [1982]. (Box 128)
    Verlag Volk und Welt]; [Berlin]
  - France dans les recits de voyages des ecrivains roumains d'aujourd'hui. by Crohmalniceanu, Ov. S., 1980. (Box 128)
    Cahiers Roumains d'Etudes Litteraires; s.l.
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, December 20, 1981, on p. 4. Offprint from CAHIERS: ROUMAINS D'ETUDES LITTERAIRES, no. 4 (1980), p. 4-16.
  - Fureya. by Koral, Fureya., [1981]. (Box 128)
    [San Grafik]; Istanbul
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. Catalog for an exhibition of works by Fureya Koral, Istanbul, 1981.
  - Hard balls. An experiment in eating! by Secunda, Arthuro., 1984. (Box 128)
    Arthuro Secunda; Paris
  - Merimee et l`Alsace. Quelques lettres inedites a Louis Schneegans. by Schneegans, Louis., 1934. (Box 128)
    Lucien Schwab; Strasbourg
    Excerpt from LA VIE EN ALSACE.
  - O juizo final. Poema. by Carvalho, Amorim de., 1948. (Box 128)
    Prometeu; Porto
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, 1951, on front flyleaf.
  - Perahim. by Jaguer, Edouard., [1978]. (Box 128)
    Editions Non Lieu; Paris
  - Plutonian ode. And other poems, 1977-1980. by Ginsberg, Allen., [1982]. (Box 128)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, December 13,1982, on half-title page.
  - Primeira Mulher. Contos. by Carvalho, Amorim de., 1952. (Box 128)
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Portugal, January 27, 1953, on half-title page.
  - Schneider. by Schneider, Gerard., 1962. (Box 128)
    Kunstverein fuer die Rheinlande und Westfalen; Duesseldorf
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on half-title page. Catalog for an exhibition of works by Gerard Schneider, Duesseldorf, 1962 at the Duesseldorf Kunsthalle Grabbeplatz.
  - Seize peintures et leur dessin. Seksten malerier og deres tegning. by Bitran., 1965. (Box 128)
    Galerie Birch; Copenhagen
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on front free endpaper. Copy 245 of 500.
  - Sens commun. Common sense. by Paine, Thomas., 1983. (Box 128)
    Editions Aubier Montaige; [Paris]
    Inscription to author from the translator, on half-title page.
  - Thorakion. Recherches iconographiques. by Rudt de Collenberg, Wipertus H., 1971. (Box 128)
    Editions E. de Boccard (Paris),"L'Erma" di Bretschnei,(Rome); Paris and Rome
    Offprint from MELANGES DE L'ECOLE FRANCAISE DE ROME, vol. 83, no. 2 (1971), p. 263-361.
  - Vrai mystere de la passion de judas. by Suares, Carlo., [1972]. (Box 128)
  - Wer war theophano? by Collenberg, Weyprecht Hugo Graf Ruedt von., 1964. (Box 128)
    Degener & Co., Inhaber Gerhard Gessner; [Frankfurt am Main and Berlin]
    Excerpt from GENEALOGISCHES JAHRBUCH, published by Zentralstelle fuer Deutsche Personen-und Familiengeschite zu Berlin.
  - Winter ist ein anderes land. by Gafita, Gabriel., [1983]. (Box 128)
    Verlag Volk und Welt; Berlin
  - Wounded, no doubt. Selected poems by Rudolf Langer. by Langer, Rudolf., 1979. (Box 128)
    Translated from the German by Ewald Osers.
  - Balzac. De Monsieur de Guermantes. Avec quatre dessins de l'auteur. by Proust, Marcel., 1950. (Box 129)
    Ides et Calendes; Neuchatel and Paris
    Limited edition of 3105(+). 3000 copies are numbered 1-3000, this copy is 2738.
  - Bericht ueber Bruno. by Breitbach, Joseph., 1962. (Box 129)
    Insel-Verlag; Frankfurt am Main
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, Paris, April 1963, on front free endpaper. Dustjacket.
  - Clemence Isaure. by Delmas, Jean-Jacques., 1984. (Box 129)
    Occitanie; Saint-Germain du Bel Air
    Inscription to Edouard Roditi from the author, on April 1984, on half-title page.
  - Colucii Salutati. De laboribus Herculis. Vol. 2. by Ullman, B.L., ed., s.d. (Box 129)
    Thesaurus Mundi; Zuerich
  - Colucii Salutati. De laboribus Herculis. vol. 1. by Ullman, B.L., ed., s.d. (Box 129)
    [Thesaurus Mundi]; [Zuerich]
  - Comedie psychologique. by Suares, Carlos., 1932. (Box 129)
    Jose Corti; Paris
  - Demetrios Capetanakis. A Greek poet in England. by Capetanakis, Demetrios., 1947. (Box 129)
    John Lehmann; London
  - Donner, a voir. by Eluard, Paul., 1939. (Box 129)